Contact

+917978683177 (Mobile) ruthkhosla17@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/juli-khosla (LinkedIn) julikhosla.github.io/portfolio/ (Personal)

Top Skills

SQL

HTML

Web Design

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

C++

JAVA

React

HTML/CSS

Angular

Juli Khosla



Technical Lead
Delta

Summary

Semior Software Developer with strong experience in the area of design and development of web and mobile applications with rich user interface and user interactivity. Worked on business projects for leading corporate sectors.

Technical expertise of almost 6 years of work experience in Web Development, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap, JQuery, React, Angular, Redux, Java, Node, Git and developing web application based on standard software development life cycle methodology- Agile.

Strong organisational and communication skill to pitch different UI styles as per the client's requirement. Dedicated learner and implementing and adapting new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Completed Bachelors Degree in Information Technology in India.

Skills:

HTML/HTML5, JavaScript, React, Redux, Angular 2/5/6, CSS, CSS Flexbox, CSS Grid, Responsive Web Design, React, Git, Bootstrap, Progressive web apps, TypeScript, Single page application, Kendo UI, SCSS, JS Design Patterns, Kafka, NPM, NodeJS, Postgres, Javascript Extension JSX, Development Tools, REST, SASS, Webpack, Wireframes, Android, Java, Unit testing.

Experience

Aivc

Technical Lead January 2022 - Present (4 months)

Surrey, British Columbia, Canada

Vultus

Full Stack Engineer

August 2020 - January 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Remote

CITIUSTECH HEALTHCARE TECHNOLOGY PRIVATE LTD

Senior Software Developer

October 2019 - July 2020 (10 months)

Mumbai Area, India

- 1. Understood client requirements for implementing new features for the application.
- 2. Worked in a team of 6 members on a weekly Sprint cycle.
- 3. Daily stand up call with the client to cover daily updates on the work progress and addressing the problems if any to come up with the best solution.
- 4. Mentoring junior team members and addressing to senior management for any delivery details and project enhancement details.

The Grex Group

Senior Frontend Developer

February 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 9 months)

- 1. Efficient hands on experience on Angular 2+ along with angular material design and React with Material UI.
- 2. Designed a web application platform for agents and a customer application for the end user using progressive web app design.
- 3. Unit testing.
- 4. Good knowledge of browser testing and debugging using Web Developer Tools..
- 5. Solid experience Telerik Kendo UI for Angular.
- 6. Strong understanding of web api and REST api calls.
- 7. Gathering requirements and ensuring to deliver the tasks on time.
- 8. Good experience in Unit testing, Bug fixing.

Infosys

3 years 10 months

System Engineer

May 2014 - February 2018 (3 years 10 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Conceptualized, planned and executed User Interface designs for a wide range of Infosys Infrastructure Management Solution Suite web project.
- Created wireframes, flow diagrams and charts. Developed the Code as per system requirements.
- Designed and developed new User Interface designs for delivery of the IIMSS product ensuring client satisfaction.
- Implemented Front-End Java pages and integrated JavaScript with Controllers in the back-end.
- Provided ongoing software support and application troubleshooting, resolving bugs and User Interface queries.
- Conducted mock up presentation and knowledge transfer to other Team members.
- Created and maintained source code documentation, test plans and laid out designs.

Senior System Engineer/ Software Developer May 2014 - February 2017 (2 years 10 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- Collaborated with users and other business teams to collect and gather system requirements for new applications.
- Translated user requirements into technical architectures, system designs and programming specifications.
- Designed, developed and maintained User interface, Web applications and Web services using Java framework on Eclipse IDE with back-end Microsoft SQL Server 2012 and MYSQL.
- Designed and developed cross-browser compatible front-end Java Servlet pages, JQuery and JavaScript components and web pages working with IIS7, SOAP and Restful Web services.
- Created, maintained, and implemented modular Batch script, SQL script, Ajax, JQuery script, AngularJS and JavaScript solutions.
- Integrated Java front-end technologies with back-end systems, Databases, MVC patterns, and third-party Web API services.
- Revamped plan for existing User Interface Design from Spring framework to Angular 2 framework.
- Managed and Implemented new methods and knowledge transfer to approach the detailed revamp plan.
- Implemented Agile scrum methodology, Test-driven development, Waterfall, SDLC, and OO design patterns to ensure delivery of high quality development work.

- Created and maintained source code documentation, test plans, wireframes, screen-flow, code diagrams and charts.
- Managed team inclination and dependency. Conducted mock up presentation and knowledge transfer to other team members.
- Provided ongoing software support and troubleshooting, resolved bugs and queries related to User Interface, and issued resolution on application system defects.
- Conducted mock up presentation and knowledge transfer to other Team members.
- Designed and developed new User Interface designs for project delivery ensuring client satisfaction.

Education

Veer Surendra Sai University Of Technology (Formerly UCE), Burla Bachelor's degree, Information Technology (2010 - 2014)

Free Code Camp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering · (2017 - 2018)

Kwantlen Polytechnic University

Postgraduate Degree, Business Administration and Management, General · (January 2022)